Guide to the Martin I. J. Griffin, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Teaching, 1959-1972; Series II
  - Course materials
    - History 21b [History of England, 1603-1964]
      - Lectures
        - The first two Georges, 1714-1760, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
        - George III: tyrant or constitutional monarch?, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
        - From the American to the French revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
        - The economic revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
        - Domestic effects of the French revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
        - Tory England, 1815-1830, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
        - The era of reform, 1780-1832, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
        - The era of reform, 1832-1865, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
        - Imperialism and the road to war, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
        - Early twentieth-century Britain, undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
        - Years of consolidation, 1918-1939, undated (Box 11, Folder 49)
        - Sir Winston Churchill and the Second World War, 1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 50)
        - The socialist revolution, 1945-1950, undated (Box 11, Folder 51)
        - Conservatives in power, 1950-1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Seminars, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Lectures
      - The Agricultural depression, undated (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - Crisis of 1346-1347, undated (Box 11, Folder 56)
      - Crown vs. Parliament in Stuart England, undated (Box 11, Folder 57)
      - Darwin, undated (Box 11, Folder 58)
      - Declaration of indulgence, undated (Box 11, Folder 59)
      - Erasmus, undated (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Feudalism, undated (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Free speech, undated (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - The House of Lords crisis, 1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
      - Jenkins' Ear, undated (Box 11, Folder 64)
      - Magna charta, undated (Box 11, Folder 65)
      - Monasteries, undated (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - Petition of right, undated (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Pope and emperor in 1046, undated (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - The scientific spirit, 1960, undated (Box 11, Folder 69)
      - Yorkshire election of 1734, undated (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Student recommendations, 1960-1970, n.d.
    General note
    Student recommendations in box 14 are restricted until January 1, 2045 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Student writings, 1960, 1964-1965, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 71-72)
  - Yale University department of history, 1961, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 73)
- Writings, 1955-1986; Series III
  The series is divided into two sections: writings by Griffin and writings about Griffin. The writings by him include newspaper columns, his scholarly papers for the Yale University Graduate School about the church in England, various speeches and poems, and articles he wrote for Yale publications. The writings about him include poems, articles in his hometown newspaper, and articles in Yale publications. All sections are arranged in chronological order.
  - By Griffin
    - Undergraduate [newspaper columns, magazine article], 1955 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Yale University Graduate School, 1956-1960, undated (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
    - Post-graduate, 1962, 1964, 1968, 1970, 1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Writings about Griffin [including Yale publications], 1955, 1957-1984, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Subject Files and Photograph, 1883-1987; Series IV
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by subject, and contains materials related to the personal and professional life of Martin Griffin, including one photograph of his father.
  - Father [Martin I. J. Griffin, Sr.]
    - General, 1883, 1891, 1938, 1955-1960, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with J.T. Reily, 1883-1892, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Photograph, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1983, 1986 undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Personal [resume, information for Who's Who in America ], 1977-1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1955-1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Yale University [appointments, fellowships, administration], 1955-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Restricted
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until 2045 January 1.
  - Student recommendations, 1960-1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    Open 2045 January 1
- Additional Material, 1953-1985; Accession 2010-M-062
  - Correspondence from Martin Griffin to John Alexander Jr.
    - 1953 Sep (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1955 Jun-Jul, Oct (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1956 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1958 Apr, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1961 Dec (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1984 Jan (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1985 Jan (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes 1980 paper written about Griffin's great-grandfather.
  - Postcards, 1953, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)